<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
  xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
  xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
  xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd"
  xmlns:trackback="http://madskills.com/public/xml/rss/module/trackback/">
  <channel>
    <title>George Anderson</title>
    <link>http://georgeanderson.com.br</link>
    <description>George Anderson Guimarães</description>
    <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2013 06:16:11 -0000</pubDate>
    <item>
      <title>Testing my REST API</title>
      <link>http://georgeanderson.com.br/post/2013/12/30/testing-rest-api.html</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Early this month I have started a journey with Javascript on the server side and Nodejs by creating this simple time-tracking tool application. After initial domain design specification - DDD yeah, I wanted to specify a REST API that would provide a simple CRUD set of operations.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2013 06:16:11 -0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://georgeanderson.com.br/post/2013/12/30/testing-rest-api.html</guid>
      <dc:date>2013-12-30T06:16:11Z</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hack the World</title>
      <link>http://georgeanderson.com.br/post/2013/12/22/hack-the-world.html</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Anybody can learn to code. That&amp;#8217;s the motto of code.org. They have this amazing infographic showing the gap of Computer Science compared to other math and science disciplines among other interesting facts. &lt;a href='http://code.org/stats'&gt;http://code.org/stats&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Dec 2013 06:35:25 -0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://georgeanderson.com.br/post/2013/12/22/hack-the-world.html</guid>
      <dc:date>2013-12-22T06:35:25Z</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>TDD with Mocha in Nodejs</title>
      <link>http://georgeanderson.com.br/post/2013/12/15/tdd-mocha-nodejs.html</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;My journey with Nodejs has just started but I don&amp;#8217;t want to throw away all the best practices and knowledge I have accumulated through the years working with other programming languages and technologies. If I had to summarize all knowledge assimilated in all those years in one word it would be: TDD.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2013 20:14:25 -0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://georgeanderson.com.br/post/2013/12/15/tdd-mocha-nodejs.html</guid>
      <dc:date>2013-12-15T20:14:25Z</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Not Falling Behind Again</title>
      <link>http://georgeanderson.com.br/post/2013/12/12/no-fall-behind.html</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;When I first saw the famous Ruby on Rails demo by David Heinemeier back in 2005, I was doing J2EE development for a Germany ERP company. Back in there Java was the most cool thing for the present and the future in my own world. My first reaction to RoR was: WOW! That is really cool. But then none of my friends really cared about it, and the senior people I used to work with were completely skeptical. &amp;#8220;You can do the same thing in Java&amp;#8221; and &amp;#8220;This is not for serious business&amp;#8221; were what I heard most. I didn&amp;#8217;t know in who to believe honestly.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Dec 2013 06:17:17 -0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://georgeanderson.com.br/post/2013/12/12/no-fall-behind.html</guid>
      <dc:date>2013-12-12T06:17:17Z</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>IDE Pitfalls</title>
      <link>http://georgeanderson.com.br/post/2013/12/01/ide-pitfalls.html</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I have participated in a code review session this week and caught an endemic issue in today&amp;#8217;s java projects: code generated by IDE. I&amp;#8217;m not against them, but just as everything else, it should be used with moderation. Consider the &lt;code&gt;Customer&lt;/code&gt; class below, getters and setters methods were automatically generated.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2013 06:18:38 -0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://georgeanderson.com.br/post/2013/12/01/ide-pitfalls.html</guid>
      <dc:date>2013-12-01T06:18:38Z</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Most Expected Movie of 2013.2</title>
      <link>http://georgeanderson.com.br/post/2013/11/25/most-expected-movie-2013.html</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I went to the movies recently to watch Gravity and saw the new trailler of Hobbit: The Desolation of Smaug. The date is coming and we are planning to watch it in the only iMax theater in town. It will be tough to get tickets in the first two weeks though.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Nov 2013 07:35:18 -0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://georgeanderson.com.br/post/2013/11/25/most-expected-movie-2013.html</guid>
      <dc:date>2013-11-25T07:35:18Z</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Life Hacks TED Talk</title>
      <link>http://georgeanderson.com.br/post/2013/11/24/life-hack-ted.html</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;If you have Netflix, you should watch their TED talk bundle about Life Hacks. The one I liked most is from Jane McGonigal: The game that can give you 10 extra years of life. She put gaming in a totally different and unexpected perspective. This is worth sharing to show some people games are not necessarily evil.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Nov 2013 06:42:18 -0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://georgeanderson.com.br/post/2013/11/24/life-hack-ted.html</guid>
      <dc:date>2013-11-24T06:42:18Z</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Aloha Ruby Conf 2012</title>
      <link>http://georgeanderson.com.br/post/2013/11/23/aloha-ruby-2012.html</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Wading through my YouTube watch list I recently stumbled on this very nice Ruby Conference lecture about code refactoring. This is very informative and impressive as you watch Ben Orenstein walk through code using vIM in light speed. The lecture is also an exemple of what I consider an almost perfect presentation where there is a nice balance between concepts and practice.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Nov 2013 13:35:27 -0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://georgeanderson.com.br/post/2013/11/23/aloha-ruby-2012.html</guid>
      <dc:date>2013-11-23T13:35:27Z</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Podcasts</title>
      <link>http://georgeanderson.com.br/post/2013/11/22/podcasts.html</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I think the first time I heard a podcast was around 2006 but only in 2009 I became a regular listener after I bought my first and only iPod (Nano 5th generation). Before the iPod the podcast experience to hear from my computer did not appeal to me. I want to hear and learn something even when I&amp;#8217;m not in front of a computer, like in bed fighting against insomnia. I had an mp3 player before that I tried to use but I could not pause and resume podcasts, making it very annoying to find exactly where I stopped. My podcast list has changed through the years and currently it looks like below.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Nov 2013 07:15:18 -0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://georgeanderson.com.br/post/2013/11/22/podcasts.html</guid>
      <dc:date>2013-11-22T07:15:18Z</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Constant Beat</title>
      <link>http://georgeanderson.com.br/post/2013/11/21/constant-beat.html</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In the year of 2000 I was introduced to this Progressive Rock band called Dream Theater (DT). This event has radically changed my music preferences for ever. I always liked Classic music (took music theory and piano classes for 1 year) but also enjoyed the distorted sound of an electric guitar. DT is the most pleasant combination of my two favorite styles: Classic music and Rock. I have a physical CD of almost every album and alternative material they produce:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Nov 2013 06:42:23 -0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://georgeanderson.com.br/post/2013/11/21/constant-beat.html</guid>
      <dc:date>2013-11-21T06:42:23Z</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Book List 2013.2</title>
      <link>http://georgeanderson.com.br/post/2013/11/20/book-list-2013.html</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Another busy year with less book reading than I would like. For non-technical books, this has been the year I made the switch to digital. I&amp;#8217;m a big fan and an old user of Kobo, but this has been only for free books. I never had such an easy digital purchase experience as with Play Books from Google. This made me give up the nice Kobo interface in favor of Play Books simplicity. My highlights for the year:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Nov 2013 06:31:55 -0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://georgeanderson.com.br/post/2013/11/20/book-list-2013.html</guid>
      <dc:date>2013-11-20T06:31:55Z</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Feeds for Thought</title>
      <link>http://georgeanderson.com.br/post/2013/11/19/feeds-for-thought.html</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The death of Google Reader was not able to pull me away from RSS feeds. I had switched to Feedly even before Google announced the intentions to shutdown Reader. I&amp;#8217;m very picky with the feeds I subscribe so I&amp;#8217;m not overwhelmed with items I will never be able to consume. I highlight a couple of them below.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Nov 2013 06:31:55 -0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://georgeanderson.com.br/post/2013/11/19/feeds-for-thought.html</guid>
      <dc:date>2013-11-19T06:31:55Z</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Websites I visit regularly</title>
      <link>http://georgeanderson.com.br/post/2013/11/17/websites-visited-regularly.html</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I have this routine in place for many years now and I don&amp;#8217;t really know when it started or how. Every week I access this fixed list of websites, one for each week day. The one per day restriction is there to avoid procrastination, however it is not religiously followed.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Nov 2013 06:44:55 -0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://georgeanderson.com.br/post/2013/11/17/websites-visited-regularly.html</guid>
      <dc:date>2013-11-17T06:44:55Z</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>My First Jekyll Post</title>
      <link>http://georgeanderson.com.br/post/2013/06/21/My-First-Jekyll-Post.html</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This is my first post using Jekyll. I intend to use GitHub to host my personal website. I had it previously hosted at Tumblr with only two posts in two years. I would expect more willingness to write now that I can do it completely from my favorite text editor or from the command line directly without having to deal with HTML formatting. Another nice thing about hosting in GitHub is that my repository and website sit together in the same place.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Jun 2013 15:18:55 -0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://georgeanderson.com.br/post/2013/06/21/My-First-Jekyll-Post.html</guid>
      <dc:date>2013-06-21T15:18:55Z</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Welcome to Jekyll!</title>
      <link>http://georgeanderson.com.br/post/2013/06/20/welcome-to-jekyll.html</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;You&amp;#8217;ll find this post in your &lt;code&gt;_posts&lt;/code&gt; directory - edit this post and re-build (or run with the &lt;code&gt;-w&lt;/code&gt; switch) to see your changes! To add new posts, simply add a file in the &lt;code&gt;_posts&lt;/code&gt; directory that follows the convention: YYYY-MM-DD-name-of-post.ext.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Jun 2013 11:18:55 -0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://georgeanderson.com.br/post/2013/06/20/welcome-to-jekyll.html</guid>
      <dc:date>2013-06-20T11:18:55Z</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Criando um Projeto JEE com Maven</title>
      <link>http://georgeanderson.com.br/post/2012/10/03/criando-um-projeto-jee-com-maven.html</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A algumas semanas uns colegas no trabalho receberam a incubência de criar uma aplicação do zero. A decisão foi por fazer uma aplicação JEE, utilizando JSF no front-end e EJB + JPA no back-end. Fui acionado para dar uma consultoria ao time e então nos reunimos para revisar pontos importantes da arquitetura, design e execução do projeto. Quando o assunto entrou em build, eu e outro amigo que também estava como consultor fomos unânimes em indicar o Maven. Como grande parte do time não tinha conhecimento no assunto, foi então que propus a seguinte estrutura. Primeiro preferi adotar a última versão do Maven (no momento a 3.0.4). Segundo tentei usar um arquétipo padrão fornecido pelo próprio Maven&lt;a href=' http://maven.apache.org/guides/introduction/introduction-to-archetypes.html'&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;, o maven-archetype-j2ee-simple.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Oct 2012 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://georgeanderson.com.br/post/2012/10/03/criando-um-projeto-jee-com-maven.html</guid>
      <dc:date>2012-10-03T00:00:00-03:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ruby on Rails - Easy Setup on Ubuntu</title>
      <link>http://georgeanderson.com.br/post/2011/12/03/ruby-on-rails---easy-setup-on-ubuntu.html</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Today I had my first experience with Ruby on Rail in a RHOK event. After a terrible experience trying to setup the environment on a Windows 7 box, I came home and started to build my own environment on a Ubuntu 10.10 system. The project I am up to contribute is the letshelp.it and it has a few version constraints: Ruby 1.8.7 Rails 3.0.7  They also have sqlite3-ruby as a requirement. Here is the installation process I took to have the basic environment necessary to start contributing to this project:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Dec 2011 00:00:00 -0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://georgeanderson.com.br/post/2011/12/03/ruby-on-rails---easy-setup-on-ubuntu.html</guid>
      <dc:date>2011-12-03T00:00:00-02:00</dc:date>
    </item>
    <dc:date>2013-12-30T06:16:11Z</dc:date>
  </channel>
</rss>